Leon Baiyu Shen Williams

E-mail leonbaiyu@gmail.com

Telephone +44 780 689 6061

I am a recent Integrated MSci Chemical Physics with Work Placement graduate with first-class honours, from the University of Glasgow, with a strong skillset in physics, programming, and chemistry. I have experience in international scientific research, having spent a year working at the Diamond Light Source synchrotron, carrying out advanced chemical analytical and ultra-high vacuum techniques, and data analysis/acquisition. Furthermore, I have practical experience in programming, for my master's project, building and implementing agent-based models in Python to study economic systems through physics concepts.

Research Experience

Masters Project: Econophysics: Agent-based modelling of markets from kinetic theory of gases and Brownian motion

Sep 2022 - Present

Supervisor: Prof. David Ireland (School of Physics Head)

- Applied physics concepts to study economic systems through agent-based models.
- Compared **kinetic theory of gases and Brownian motion** to individual interactions in markets through simulation of these agent-based models.
- Developed and adapted these models to produce emergent phenomena resembling economic systems, such as wealth distributions and stock price fluctuations.
- Using JavaScript to visualise interactive results on a webpage/server.
- Software was developed in Python and JupyterLab paired with GitHub and Docker.
- Incorporated a range of libraries including mesa-ABM, Scipy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, and Pandas alongside standard software development practices.

Year in Industry Work Placement – Diamond Light Source Ltd Supervisor: Dr David A. Duncan

Sep 2021 - Aug 2022

- Studying 2D materials including Graphene, and graphene-like films in **ultra-high vacuum** (UHV) at the **Diamond Light Source synchrotron**.
- Utilised chemical surface analysis techniques including X-ray and electron diffraction and spectroscopy, and microscopy.
- Carried out varied data analysis for respective techniques, often extracting signals from raw instrument data.
- Utilised scripting for automated data acquisition through instrument control using Jython
- High level data analysis involved Python, its associated libraries, and MATLAB, as well as FORTRAN for X-ray scattering calculations. Optimised using particle swarm optimization methods (PSO) run on the STFC-hosted SCARF high performance computing cluster.
- Balanced workload of group and independent projects.
- Carried out research in collaboration with/on behalf of groups in other international universities including the Technical University of Munich.
- Involved in numerous **customer-facing tours** of the facility and **mentorship programme** for supporting newer employees during their first 3 months working at the company.
- Acquired technical skills for the **construction**, **mounting**, and **setup** of **UHV equipment**.

Publications: Using polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons for graphene growth on Cu(111) under ultrahigh vacuum – Appl. Phys. Lett. 121, 191603 (2022), **3 more due to be published this year.**

Education

2018 – 2023 Integrated MSci Chemical Physics - University of Glasgow, Scotland Grade: First Class

Relevant Modules:

Nuclear & Particle Physics, Quantum Information, Atomic Systems, Electromagnetic Theory, Mathematical Methods, Quantum Mechanics, Thermal Physics, Waves & Diffraction, Solid State Physics, Physical Chemistry, Inorganic Chemistry, Organic Chemistry

2012 - 2018 James Gillespie's High School

Advanced Higher: Mathematics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (A)

Higher: Mathematics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Computing (A), Biology (A)

National 5: Mathematics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Computer Science (A), Biology (A),

Geography (A), French (A), English (A)

Technical Skills

My physics labs have been based around developing general experimental problem-solving:

 Applying critical thinking and problem solving to understand, design, and execute indepth physics-based experiments, within a short time frame and with limited preparatory knowledge (e.g. Laser Interferometry, Polarisation, Nuclear and Electron Spin Resonance).

Developing programming proficiencies:

- Python, FORTRAN and MATLAB for various data analysis.
- Additionally, LiveCode, SQL, HTML and CSS, and project methodologies (Waterfall and Agile).
- Skilled in Windows and Unix-based operating systems.
- Experienced in the use of **Docker**, **GitHub**, **Linux**, **high performance computer clusters**. Practical Techniques:
 - Chemical analytical (IR/NMR/UV/Vis/X-ray Spectroscopy, Mass Spectrometry, TLC)
 - X-ray and Electron Diffraction based techniques (XSW, LEED, ARPES, PhD)
 - Scanning Tunneling Microscopy
 - Ultra-high vacuum systems
 - Standard Chemical Techniques.

Other Experience and Extra-curricular activities

Summer Camp Counselor - American Youth Foundation

Jun - Sep 2019

Responsible for organising events for large groups of all ages while simultaneously managing a cabin full of kids; planning and coordinating with other staff members a varying schedule that required forethought as well as the flexibility to react and adapt to situations that arose.

Fundraising - JGHS South Africa Trust

Oct 2017 - Feb 2018

Fundraising for a trust set up for partner school in South Africa; Played a primary role in organising fundraising events; enrolling volunteers, contributors and attracting sponsors (e.g. Santander Bank).

Research Assistant Placement at Edinburgh Royal Observatory

Nov - Dec 2017

Supporting the stakeholder engagement coordinator in the Space and Satellite innovation programme at Edinburgh Royal Observatory; selecting and writing concise accessible reports on topics of interest in astronomy (e.g. the potential of Lagrangian Points for stationing satellites).

Men's Captain - Glasgow University Ultimate Team

April 2020 – April 2021

- Managed a competitive team and played a primary leadership role in running a 100+ person University Sports Club.
- Led the team through novel challenges posed by the pandemic through forward-thinking, planning, and development of intake forecasts and risk assessments.
- Demonstrated leadership skills in taking initiative, establishing effective division of labour, and utilising the abilities and enthusiasm of committee members.

Home Projects

April - Sep 2020

- Self-directed and curiosity-driven study during interruption of formal education.
- Completed challenging projects such as reverse-engineering hardware (modifying Raspberry Pi, repurposing IR receiver from an old TV and repairing various technology), electroplating and heat treatment in making jewellery and crafting complex knife handles.
- Involved online research and utilising various resources such as online forums (e.g. StackOverflow for Python) for problem-solving, experimentation and learning.
- Employed practical skills including soldering and working with circuits and metal/woodwork.

Languages: English (Native), Spoken Mandarin (Intermediate Level), French (National 5)